Guide to the Albert Rees Papers, 1966-1992 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Albert Rees papers 1966-1992 and undated
Rees, Albert, 1921-
10.5 linear feet Extent: 6300 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.01076
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Portions of the collection are restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Albert Rees Papers were received as a gift to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1993.
Biographical Note
Economics professor and administrator at Princeton University. Headed Gerald Ford's Council on Wage and Price Stability.
Collection Overview
Collection contains correspondence, lectures, writings, and course notes. There is testimony involving a union dispute. Some correspondence is divided by name of correspondent.
Subject Headings
Employment (Economic theory); Wages; Labor unions; Unemployment-Economic aspects; United States -- Economic policy
Contents of Collection
- Accession # 1993-0204
  Access is restricted; for more details, please see the reference staff of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
  - My Reprints (Box 1)
  - United Aircraft Case (Box 1)
  - Lincoln School (Box 1)
  - Nabisco (Box 1)
  - BLS—Wage Changes (Box 1)
  - Co-ops (Box 1)
  - Speech, April 9, 1976 before the Plans and Resources Committee (Box 1)
  - Personal (Box 1)
  - National Institute of Health (Box 1)
  - Citibank (Box 1)
  - Committee on Prices; correspondence (Box 1)
  - Book Reviews (Box 1)
  - Negative Income tax (Box 1)
  - Testimony before the House Committee on Govt. Operations (9/17/75) (Box 1)
  - Biographical information (Box 1)
  - Personal Correspondence: a-f (Box 1)
  - Personal Correspondence: g-m (Box 1)
  - Personal Correspondence: n-r (Box 1)
  - Personal Correspondence: s (Box 1)
  - Personal Correspondence: t-z (Box 1)
  - Noncash Benefits (Box 1)
  - Letter on Welfare Reform (Box 1)
  - Recommendations: a-m (Box 1)
  - Recommendations: n-z (Box 1)
  - Policy Research Workshop in Incomes Policy (Box 1)
  - The James Lecture: 10/8/75 (Box 1)
  - NYT Article (Box 1)
  - Journal of Political Economy (Box 1)
  - Letters to the Editor (Box 1)
  - Ed-Op (Box 1)
  - Food Industry Committee (Box 1)
  - Adam Smith Essay (Box 1)
  - My course notes and grades- Chicago (Box 1)
  - Journal refereeing (Box 1)
  - Research on Urban Poverty Conference 1969 (Box 1)
  - Tax Based Incomes Policy (Box 1)
  - Econ 102 Grades (Fall 1977) (Box 1)
  - Thesis Supervision (Box 1)
  - Econ 313: Manpower and Labor Problems (Spring 1977) (Box 1)
  - Econ 314: Undergrad Labor (Box 1)
  - USSR Trip (Box 1)
  - PA 511-A, 512-A (Box 1)
  - Econ 531: Graduate Labor (Box 1)
  - Princeton: 1964 and before (Box 1)
  - Committee on Unemployment Statistics (Box 1)
  - Misc. Students (Box 1)
  - Historical Statistics (Box 1)
  - Ulman Comment (Box 1)
  - Chicago Thesis Supervision (Box 1)
  - Econ 300 (Box 1)
  - Econ 340 (Box 1)
  - Econ 240 (Box 1)
  - Econ 203 A, B, C—Old Exams (Box 1)
  - Econ 341 (Box 1)
  - Chicago Departmental 1955 (Box 1)
  - Thesis Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Econ 102 (72-73) (Box 1)
    Correspondence. Other section from A-H can be found at end of Box 3.
  - Ethel Jones (Box 2)
  - Robin Kendrick (Box 2)
  - Bill Kruskal (Box 2)
  - H.G. Lewis (Box 2)
  - Lurie (Box 2)
  - Bette Mahoney (Box 2)
  - Mansfield (Box 2)
  - Denton Marks (Box 2)
  - Mulvey (Box 2)
  - Oaxaca, Ronald (Box 2)
  - Offner (Box 2)
  - Pencavel (Box 2)
  - L. Rapping (Box 2)
  - Rowlatt (Box 2)
  - Dan Saks (Box 2)
  - David Shapiro (Box 2)
  - Sharon Smith (Box 2)
  - David Stager (Box 2)
  - Jan Svenjnar (Box 2)
  - Rita Sweeney (Box 2)
  - George P. Shultz (Box 2)
  - David Taylor (Box 2)
  - A.P. Thirwall (Box 2)
  - Joe Ullman (Box 2)
  - Kathy Yaeger (Box 2)
    Printed material.
  - The Economics of Work and Pay, 1973 (Box 2)
  - The Economics of Work and Pay (Third Edition), 1984 (Box 2)
  - The Economics of Work and Pay (Fourth Edition), 1988 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Retirement in the Arts and Sciences, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Real Wages in Manufacturing 1890-1914, 1961 (Box 2)
  - La influencia economica de los sindicatos en los Estados Unidos, 1987 (Box 2)
  - The Economics of Trade Unions, 1962 (Box 2)
  - The Economics of Trade Unions (Revised Edition), 1977 (Box 2)
  - Striking a Balance: Making National Economic Policy (soft and hard covers), 1984 (Box 2)
  - The Economics of Work and Pay (Second Edition), 1989 (Box 2)
  - Reflections on Labor and Learning in America, 1988 (Box 2)
  - American Academy of Sciences (Box 3)
  - American Economic Association (Box 3)
  - Bethany College (Box 3)
  - Brookings (Box 3)
  - Center for Economic Development (Box 3)
  - Univ. of Chicago Press (Box 3)
  - Center for Advanced Study (Box 3)
  - Harper and Row (Box 3)
  - Council on Wage and Price Stability (Box 3)
  - Congressional Budget Office; Panel of Economic Advisers (Box 3)
  - Council of Economic Advisers (Box 3)
  - Construction Industry Stabilization Committee (Box 3)
  - Coalition of Northeast Governors (Box 3)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER) (1952-57) (Box 3)
  - NBER (1977 and later) (Box 3)
  - NBER (1950s and 1960s) (Box 3)
  - Public Employment Relations Commission (Box 3)
  - Treasury Consultants (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Government (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Business Organizations (Box 3)
  - General Learning (Box 3)
  - Prices and Income (Box 3)
  - Foreign (Box 3)
  - University of California (Box 3)
  - University of Chicago (Box 3)
  - Cornell (Box 3)
  - Northwestern (Box 3)
  - Harvard (Box 3)
  - MIT (Box 3)
  - Northwestern (Box 3)
  - Penn (Box 3)
  - Princeton (Box 3)
  - Princeton University Press (Box 3)
  - Other Publishers (Box 3)
  - Rochester (Box 3)
  - Rutgers (Box 3)
  - Social Science Research Council (Box 3)
  - Stanford (Box 3)
  - Yale (Box 3)
  - Bill Bowen (Box 3)
  - Phelps Brown (Box 3)
  - Cain (Box 3)
  - Comay (Box 3)
  - Paul Davidson (Box 3)
  - David Dodge (Box 3)
  - Henry Farber (Box 3)
  - Randy Filer (Box 3)
  - Jack Frisch (Box 3)
  - Harry J. Gilman (Box 3)
  - Judith Gross (Box 3)
  - Christine Greenhalgh (Box 3)
  - Gujarati (Box 3)
  - Linda Halpern (Box 3)
  - John Ham (Box 3)
  - D. Hershfield (Box 3)
  - Barry Hughes (Box 3)
  - William and Mary (Box 4)
  - Drafts of miscellaneous papers (Box 4)
  - Faculty Retirement Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Mellon (Box 4)
  - News Stories—clippings and copies of clippings (Box 4)
  - Advisory Committee (Box 4)
  - Oberlin Investment (Box 4)
  - Other Studies (misc. research info. and papers) (Box 4)
  - Bowen Book (Box 4)
  - Wilson Thesis (Box 4)
  - National Institutes of Health, group photograph (Box 4)
  - Ph.D. Worksheets (Box 4)
  - Ph.D. Data (Box 4)
  - Injury (Box 4)
  - Oberlin (Box 4)
  - Mandatory Retirement Project (Box 4)
  - Offprints of Changing Economic Realities and the Changing Role of Unions (Box 4)
  - (Box 4)
  - Manuscript: The Economics of Work and Pay (fifth edition) (Box 4)
  - Recording for the Blind (1) (mss.) (Box 5)
  - Recording for the Blind (2) (mss.) (Box 5)
  - Referrals (File #1) (Box 5)
  - Rees - Ph.D. Paper (Box 5)
  - Rutgers (Box 5)
  - Sloan Foundation (Box 5)
  - Students Letters of Recommendation (Box 5)
  - Articles and Publications Reviewed (File #3, 1986) (Box 5)
  - Lectures 1979 (Box 5)
  - US Government et al. (Box 5)
  - Universities (Box 5)
  - William and Mary (Box 5)
  - Paper: Ellwood / Summers (Box 5)
  - Royalties and Contracts (Box 5)
  - Black Youth Unemployment (Box 5)
  - Douglas Paper (Box 5)
  - Executive Magazine: Strengthening the Market (Box 5)
  - Grants Magazine (Box 5)
  - The Conference Board Magazine (Box 5)
  - Freeman / Medoff's What do Unions Do? (Box 5)
  - Testimony before the Senate Subcommittee on Employment and Productivity (1982) (Box 5)
  - Testimony: Task Force on Science Policy, House Committee (Box 5)
  - Testimony before subcommittee on Banking (Box 5)
  - Productivity Statistics (Box 5)
  - Manufacturing Unions (Box 5)
  - Univ. of Chicago Press—Correspondence (Box 5)
  - New Edition: The Economics of Trade Unions (Box 5)
  - Striking a Balance: Reviews (Box 5)
  - Albert Rees / Daniel Hamermesh: Economics of Work and Pay (3rd edition) (Box 5)
  - Youth Unemployment (Essay on) (Box 5)
  - Macro Models of Labor Management (Box 5)
  - Philanthropy Monthly (1984) (Box 5)
  - Tax Reform (Box 5)
  - Incomes Policy Session (1980) (Box 5)
  - Sproull Symposium (1984) (Box 5)
  - Randy Filer (Box 5)
  - Harold Hochman (Box 5)
  - Julian Simon (Box 5)
  - Hugo Rees Trust (Box 5)
  - Survey Data (Box 5)
  - American U. data (Box 5)
  - LAC- Flows (Box 5)
  - PUU- Age Distributions (Box 5)
  - PRC- Age Distributions (Box 5)
  - LAC- Age Distributions (Box 5)
  - Charts and Misc. (Box 5)
  - Revised Flows (Box 6)
  - Eucub Distributions (Box 6)
  - Mailing list to participants (Box 6)
  - Charts (Box 6)
  - PRU Flows (Box 6)
  - LAU Flows (Box 6)
  - PUU Flows (Box 6)
  - PUC Flows (Box 6)
  - PRC Flows (Box 6)
  - LAU- Age Distributions (Box 6)
  - PUC- Age Distributions (Box 6)
  - PRU- Age Distributions (Box 6)
  - Loose material of the same nature as above (Box 6)
  - Offprints (Box 6)
  - IRRA- (1990) (Box 6)
  - Personal Correspondence (written by Rees) (Box 6)
  - AEA Meetings (1990) (Box 6)
  - AEA Session (Box 6)
  - Personal (Box 6)
  - Bibliography (9 copies of photograph of Rees) (Box 6)
  - AAAS Meetings (Box 6)
  - AAAS Committee on Investment and Finance (Box 6)
  - American Economics Association (Box 7)
  - Alaska Fisheries Case (Box 7)
  - AEA Search Committee (Box 7)
  - American Enterprise Institute (Box 7)
  - Ad-Hoc AEA Committee on Publishers (Box 7)
  - Baruch (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Mellon (Visiting Committee) School of Urban and Public Affairs (Box 7)
  - Brookings Institution (Box 7)
  - Consortium on Financing Higher Education (Box 7)
  - Cornell (Box 7)
  - Census Committee (Box 7)
  - Advisory Committee: Center for the Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Box 7)
  - University of Chicago (Box 7)
  - Council on Wage and Price Stability (Box 7)
  - Fringe Benefits (Box 7)
  - International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis (Box 7)
  - Independent Sector (Box 7)
  - IRRA (Box 7)
  - Loran Commission (Box 7)
  - Math Tech (Box 7)
  - Michigan State (Box 7)
  - Mincer Paper (Box 7)
  - Clark Kerr paper (Box 7)
  - University of Minnesota (Box 7)
  - MIT—General Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Misc. Organizations (Box 7)
  - Mathematica Policy Research (Box 7)
  - MIT—Corporation Visiting Committee Dept, Of Economics (Box 7)
  - National Research Council Committee on National Statistics (Box 7)
  - National Research Council (Box 7)
  - Nabisco Brands (Box 7)
  - National Institute of Health (Box 7)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research (Box 7)
  - New York State Doctoral Project (Box 7)
  - Oberlin College Board of Trustees (Box 7)
  - Oberlin College Commencement 1981 (Box 7)
  - Princeton 1978-79 (Box 7)
  - Princeton 1980 (Box 7)